Guide to the Rice University Biochemistry Department records, 1972-2006 UA 141
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Biochemistry Department records
1972-2006
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Department of Biochemistry.
UA 141
15 Linear Feet 29 boxes
Biochemistry Department files documenting the daily business of the department, including records of seminars, faculty members' grants, department brochures, budget files, and more. Faculty members represented include but are not limited to Kathleen Beckingham, George N. Bennett, Janet Braam, Susan Gibson, Raymon M. Glantz, Richard H. Gomer, Michael Gustin, Kathleen S. Matthews, John S. Olson, Graham A. Palmer, George N. Phillips, Jr., and Michael Stern.
Biographical / Historical
The Department of Biochemistry and Cell Biology conducts exciting research in emerging bioscience fields, educates graduate and undergraduate students, and communicates advances in these fields to the scientific community and beyond. Particular fields recognized among faculty pursuits include biochemistry, metabolic engineering, biophysics, structural biology, microbiology, molecular genetics, neurobiology, developmental biology, plant biology, and signal transduction, among other areas. The breadth of the program enables graduate students to have a wide spectrum of topics available when choosing their area of concentration and affords undergraduates ample opportunity to explore their individual interests in research. Cooperation with a number of centers and specialized training programs at Rice and the TMC further enrich the academic environment. Innovative teaching and mentoring programs have established a culture emphasizing quality and communication skills that has achieved greater impact through outreach programs that promote bioscience education. (excerpted from Department of Biochemistry and Cell Biology home page, http://biochem.rice.edu/)
Scope and Contents
Biochemistry Department files documenting the daily business of the department, including records of seminars, faculty members' grants, department brochures, budget files, and more. Faculty members represented include but are not limited to Kathleen Beckingham, George N. Bennett, Janet Braam, Susan Gibson, Raymon M. Glantz, Richard H. Gomer, Michael Gustin, Kathleen S. Matthews, John S. Olson, Graham A. Palmer, George N. Phillips, Jr., and Michael Stern.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research except where noted.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Provenance
Transferred to Woodson Research Center, 2007 and 2013
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
syllabi; letters (correspondence); notes; reports
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University.
- Series I: Alphabetical files A-M, 240752
  - Account Coding Changes, 240881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACS Directory of Graduate Research, 240880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advanced Technology, 240879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Air Compressor, 240878 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Albertyn Award, 240877 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Animals, 240876 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Animal Room 319A, 240875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Animal Safety Facility, 240874 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Babcock, Gerald, 240873 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bartel--ATP, 240872 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baylor Subcontract, 240871 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baylor Subcontract, 240870 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beckingham, Kathleen, 240869 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beckingham--American Cancer Society, 240868 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Beckingham--ATP, 240867 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Beckingham--NIH, 240866 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Beckingham--NSF, 240865 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Beckingham Squibb Account, 240864 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Beckingham--TATP, 240863 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Beckingham--Texas Technologies, 240862 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Beckman Scholars, 240861 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bennett--Army, 240860 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bennett--DOE, 240859 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bennett--NIH, 240858 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bennett--NSF, 240857 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bennett--NSF, 240856 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bennett--Rudolph, 240855 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bennett--Rudolph, 240854 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bennett--TATP, 240853 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bennett--Texas Technologies, 240852 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bennett--USDA, 240851 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bennett--Welch Grant, 240850 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Neill Binford, 240849 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Binford Palmer's Authorization Number, 240848 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Biochemistry Department Gift, 240847 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Biology, 240846 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Biomedical Support and Grants, 240845 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Braam--NASA, 240844 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Braam--NIH, 240843 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Braam--NSF, 240842 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Braam--USDA, 240841 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 240840 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brochures 1974, 240839 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brochures 1975-1976, 240838 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Brochures 1976-1977, 240837 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brochures 1977-1978, 240836 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brochures 1978-1979, 240835 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brochures 1979-1980, 240834 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brochures 1980-1981, 240833 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brochures 1981-1982, 240832 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - BRSG Account, 240831 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - BRSG Award Letters, 240830 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - BRSG Report and Publications, 240829 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brucker, Eric, 240828 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Budget, 240827 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Building, 240826 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Buildings--Biomedical Lab, 240825 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bulk Mail, 240824 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, 240823 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Campbell, 240822 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Campbell--NSF, 240821 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry Department, 240820 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clarage--NIH Fellowship, 240819 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Clayton Foundation, 240818 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Comptroller's Office, 240817 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Computer Service, 240816 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Computer Survey, 240815 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence to Faculty, 240814 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1979 and 1980, 240813 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Account, 240812 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - De Hostos, 240811 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Department Administrator, 240810 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Different Letters, 240809 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Different Records, 240808 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - DORCUS, 240807 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Equipment Inventory 1993, 240806 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Exhaust hoods, 240805 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Questionnaires, 240804 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gibson, Quentin H., 240803 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gibson (Q)--NIH, 240802 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Gibson, Susan--DOE, 240801 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Gibson (S)--USDA, 240800 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Glantz 88-89, 240799 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Glantz--NSF, 240798 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Glidon and Physical Plant, 240797 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Global, 240796 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Gomer, 240795 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Gomer, 240794 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Gomer--Gift Account, 240793 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gomer--March of the Dimes, 240792 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Gomer--NASA, 240791 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Greenwood Lab, 240790 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gustin, Michael, 240789 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Gustin--American Cancer Soc., 240788 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gustin--NSF, 240787 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Gustin--NSF, 240786 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gustin--NSF, 240785 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gustin--NSF Undergraduates, 240784 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Haltom, Marsha, 240783 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - High Emprise, 240782 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hughes, Randolph, 240781 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Injury, 240780 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Invention Agreement, 240779 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Invoices, 240778 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Job Openings 1981, 240777 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Johnson (K.)--Burrough Wellcome, 240776 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry Acc., 240775 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Kim, Hong-Seok, 240774 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Kimbrell-American Cancer, 240773 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - King, 240772 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - King--Shared Instrumentation Grant, 240771 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - King--Welch Grant, 240770 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Knapp, 240769 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Konisky, 240768 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory Personnel, 240767 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Matthews, K., 240766 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Matthews, 240765 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Matthews, 240764 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Matthews, 240763 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Matthews, 240762 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Matthews, 240761 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Matthews, 240760 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Matthews, 240759 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Matthews--Clayton Foundation, 240758 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Matthews--Keck Foundation, 240757 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Matthews--Mathers, 240756 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Matthews--NIH, 240755 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Matthews--Recombinant DNA Molecules, 240754 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Matthews--Small Equipment 1992-1993, 240753 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series II: Alphabetical files N-Z, 240637
  - Nikonowicz—NIH, 240751 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NSF Renovation Account, 240750 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - NSF Undergraduates, 240749 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Obermeier, Donna, 240748 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Olson, 240747 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Olson, 240746 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Olson, 240745 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Olson, 240744 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Olson--ATP, 240743 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Olson--NSF, 240742 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Olson--Research Support Account, 240741 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Palmer, 240740 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Palmer, 240739 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Palmer, 240738 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Palmer, 240737 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Palmer, 240736 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Palmer, 240735 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Papoutsakis--NSF, 240734 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Pfizer Inc., 240733 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Phillips, 240732 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Phillips, 240731 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Phillips--NIH, 240730 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Phillips--NIH Boston Subcontract, 240729 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Phillips--NSF, 240728 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Phillips--NSF, 240727 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Phillips--NSF Keck Training, 240726 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Phillips--NSF/NCSA, 240725 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Phillips--NSF Training Grant, 240724 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Phillips--NSF/Zhou, 240723 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Price(M)--MDA, 240722 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Price--MDA Grant, 240721 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Price--Smiekel Foundation, 240720 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Property Disposal 1988, 240719 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Property Disposal 1989, 240718 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Proposals, 240717 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Purchasing and Accounting Clerk, 240716 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Quiocho, 240715 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reader File 1981, 240714 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reader File Jan-June 1982, 240713 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reader File July-Dec 1982, 240712 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reader File 1983, 240711 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations--General, 240710 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rudolph, 240709 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Rudolph, 240708 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Rudolph, 240707 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Rudolph, 240706 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Rudolph--ATP, 240705 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Rudolph--Immunex Corp., 240704 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rudolph--NASA, 240703 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Rudolph--NIH, 240702 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Rudolph--NIH, 240701 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Rudolph--NIH, 240700 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Rudolph--NSF, 240699 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Rudolph--THECB, 240698 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Rudolph--Welch Grant, 240697 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Safety, 240696 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Schedules, 240695 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Schedules, 240694 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Schroepfer, 240693 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Schroepfer, 240692 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Schroepfer, 240691 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Schroepfer, 240690 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Schroepfer, 240689 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Schroepfer, 240688 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Schroepfer, 240687 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Schroepfer, 240686 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Schroepfer, 240685 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Schroepfer, 240684 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Schroepfer, 240683 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Schroepfer July 1991-June 1992, 240682 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Schroepfer--ATP, 240681 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Schroepfer--Loony Account, 240680 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Schroepfer--March of Dimes, 240679 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Schroepfer--March of Dimes, 240678 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Schroepfer--NIH, 240677 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Schroepfer--Upjon, 240676 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Secretarial Personnel, 240675 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Seminars 1972, 240674 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Seminars 1973, 240673 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Seminars 1974, 240672 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Seminars 1975, 240671 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Seminars 1976, 240670 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Seminars 1977, 240669 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Seminars 1978, 240668 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Seminars 1979, 240667 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Seminars 1980, 240666 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Seminars 1981, 240665 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Seminars 1983, 240664 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Seminars 1984, 240663 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Seminars 1984-1985, 240662 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Seminars 1985-1986, 240661 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Seminars 1986-1987, 240660 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Seminars 1987-1988, 240659 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Seminars (PhD) 1987-1988, 240658 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Seminars (PhD) 1988-1989, 240657 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Shaw-Baylor, Andrea, 240656 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Sherrill, Bete, 240655 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Sherril, Bete, 240654 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Small Instrumentation Grant, 240653 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Stern--American Heart Assoc., 240652 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Stern--Neurofibromatosis, 240651 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Stern--NIH, 240650 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Stern--Start up Account, 240649 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Stewart 1988-1989, 240648 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Stewart 1988-1989, 240647 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Student Employees, 240646 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Student Recruitment, 240645 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - University of Texas, 240644 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Welch Reception 1989, 240643 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Welch Grant--Gomer, 240642 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Welch Grant--Walker, 240641 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Work study, 240640 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Xerox Charges, 240639 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Xerox Charges 1990, 240638 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Series III: Addendum, Bulk, 1990-2007 1972-2006; 1990-2007; 240611
  - Annual Reports, 1990-2005; 240631
    - Annual Report, 1990; 240636 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 1996; 240635 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report, 2003; 240634 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report, 2004; 240633 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report, 2005; 240632 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Course Materials, 1996-2006; 240620
    - Bioscience 301--Exams (Restricted), Fall 1997; 240630 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Bioscience 301--Lecture Notes, 1997; 240629 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Bioscience 352--Exams (Restricted), Spring 1998; 240628 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Bioscience 352--Lecture Notes, Spring 1998; 240627 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Bioscience 421--Exams (Restricted), 2003-2006; 240626 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Bioscience 421--Lecture Notes, 1996; 240625 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Bioscience 421--Lecture Notes (1 of 3), 2003; 240624 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Bioscience 421--Lecture Notes (2 of 3), 2003; 240623 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Bioscience 421--Lecture Notes (3 of 3), 2003; 240622 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Bioscience 421--Lecture Notes, n.d.; 240621 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Department Materials, 1972-1998; 240612
    - Department Catalog, 1990; 240619 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Information Systems, 1990-1991; 240618 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Magneto Optical Disk, 1989-1992; 240617 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Publications, Glantz et al. (1 of 2), 1972-1990; 240616 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Publications, Glantz et al. (2 of 2), 1972-1990; 240615 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Receptor Tachykinin I-V Study. Graph Readout., 2/20/1998; 240614 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Research Council, 1998; 240613 (Box 29, Folder 22)